ARSLAN ALI

AGRIBUSINESS GRADUATE

https://www.linkedin.com/in/arslan-ali-00b930162/ • Age: 21



Summary

Experienced Agribusiness Graduate with a demonstrated history of working in the Banking, Textile & Finishing Mills, Dairy, Fertilizer and Pesticides Industry. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements. Skilled in Analytical Skills, MOS Office, Accounting, Self-MGT, Effective Communication, Multi-tasking, Time-MGT.

Education

Sukkur Institute of Business Administration University (3.31/4) BBA (AGRIBUSINESS)

• +92-306-2607782 • arslanali.agriba15@iba-suk.edu.pk

Sukkur, Pakistan 2015-2019

Achieved Sindh Endowment Scholarship by getting position in top 5 students out of 40 students' batch.

Experience

SYNGENTA Larkana, Pakistan

Leading agriculture company helping to improve global food security by enabling millions of farmers to make better use of available resources. Syngenta is the producer (manufacturer) of chemical pesticides products with brand name

Sales Operations Intern: June 2019 – July 2019

- Built strong relationships with clients by following up on previous purchases and suggesting new products.
- Dealt with the franchisers, sales, distribution, and supply chain activities with & under the supervision of the supervisors including; Franchisers, Field Officers, Senior Technical Sales Officer (STSO) & Syngenta field team.
- Do the vegetables & rice farm visits, group discussion, product sale call & product orientation of the Refit & Virtako product along with other products.
- Identified and communicated customer needs to supply chain capacity and quality teams.
- Worked alongside retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentations and productsales call.

MUMTAZ FERTILIZER & PESTICIDES MARKAZ

Naudero, Pakistan

Open market retail shop, it is the retail seller of the chemical pesticides & fertilizer that sells directly to end-user

Assistant to Manager: April 2019 – June 2019

- Attained expert level of product knowledge, becoming go-to person for major sales & vendor negotiations.
- Built strong relationships with clients by following up on previous purchases and suggesting new products.
- Human Resource Management: Analyzed & understood the HRM practices & management at retail shop level.
- Operation Management: Learnt the management operations at the fertilizer & pesticides shop in the open market from fertilizer & pesticides receiving to selling to end-users, farmer advice to creating long-term customer equity.
- Office Management: Learnt & analyze the current practices at the management level of agro-chemical retail shop, proper documentation, record keeping.
- Procurement: Interactive with the fertilizer & pesticides field officers, TSO, & RSM and strengthened merchandising & promotional strategies to drive customer engagement and boost sales.

ENGRO FERTILIZER LIMITED

Larkana, Pakistan

Engro Fertilizer is the producer (manufacturer) of chemical fertilizers products with brand name Engro. Sales Operations Intern: March 2019 - April 2019

- Dealt with the dealers, sales, distribution, warehouse, supply chain & Zarkhez business unit activities.
- Did the vegetables & wheat farm visits, group discussion, soil sampling, sale call & product orientation of the Zarkhez & Zabardast Urea along with other SFB products.

- Implemented up-selling strategies, encompassing recommendation of fertilizer and complementary purchases.
- Tracked stock using company inventory management software (SAP & WMS) with & under the supervision of the four supervisors including; Warehouse Incharge, DO, SO, Area Incharge of the Larkana (SMDO) & Engro fertilizer field team.
- Worked alongside retail representatives to boost sales by enhancing product presentations and productsale call.

SAPPHIRE TEXTILE & FINISHING MILLS LIMITED

Sheikhupura, Raiwind, Pakistan

Sapphire is the leader among the largest integrated textile producers in Pakistan.

Business Operations Intern: January 2019 – March 2019

- Attained expert level of product knowledge, becoming go-to person for major sales and vendor negotiations.
- Dealt with systems for inventory control, merchandising, financial reports and schedules, dramatically increasing operational efficiency.
- Human Resource Management: Analyzed & understood the HRM practices & management at organizational level.
- Operation Management: Learnt the management operations at the Textile & Finishing Mills in the State-of-Art units of the organization from raw-cotton receiving to selling garment & greige fabric to customers, customer advice & follow-up to creating long-term customer equity.
- Office Management: Learnt & analyze the current practices at the management level of textile & industrial sector, proper documentation, record keeping, follow-up, etc.

HBL – HABIB BANK LIMITED

Tando Muhammad Khan, Pakistan

HBL – Habib Bank Limited is the Pakistan's foremost commercial & largest private Bank since its inception. Summer Student Intern: July 2018 – August 2018

- Analyzed, Observed and Tacit the job, tasks & responsibilities of the AFO, managed 15 agriculture loans & farmers along with & under the supervision of two agriculture finance officer (AFO's).
- Dealt with farmers, do documentation of the financing, reporting & agriculture field visit for confirm financing to farmers with AFO's.
- Knowledgeable of appropriate documentation of loan renewal, and Customer dealing in urban & rural branch.
- Paid out time in RHQ, tacit the practices of agricultural loaning, understand the rotary of loan installments and required documents at RHQ for loaning approval.
- Paid out time in rural branch & knowledgeable about agricultural banking practices, management & customer dealing.

Academic Activities

PROJECT ON PRINCIPLE OF MANAGEMENT

Sukkur, Pakistan

Team based project report of on management principles (Fatima Fertilizer Company Limited). *Team Lead Member: January* 2018 – May 2018

- Attained the real management exposure through covering the outcomes of the Decision-making,

- Organizational Design, Motivation, & Ethical practices in the "Fatima Fertilizer Company Limited."
- Conducted interview with the DSM of "Fatima Fertilizer Company Limited" and come up with excellent written report but again rocked up with the presentation with effective teamwork, collaboration, research work, contents, well organized, & managed work.

Honors and Awards

ACADEMIC SCHOLARHIPS

Sukkur, Pakistan

- Received the Sindh Endowment scholarship from SIBAU (2016-2019)

AWARD (PRIME MINISTER LAPTOP AWARD)

Sukkur, Pakistan

Received merit-based Laptop Award of Prime Minister's Laptop Scheme from SIBAU (2017)
 Additional

- *Skills:* SPSS 2.3, MOS Office, Emailing, Problem-Solving Skills, Communications Skills, Negotiation Skills, Financial & Managerial Accounting, Agribusiness & Ecommerce, CRM, Team, Project MGT.

Certifications: Six-Month Computer Course (Computer World Naudero, 2010)
Microsoft Office 2013 (Sukkur IBA University, 2017)

- *Interests:* Sports, Travelling, Reading.

- Language: English, Sindhi, Urdu, Punjabi